Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and it's the start of a very new year so we have some interesting
我是Catherine，现在是一个全新一年的开始，所以我们今天为大家准备了一些有趣的
vocabulary for you today about the new year.
关于新年的词汇。
That's right.
没错。
So we are starting a new year.
所以我们正在开启新的一年。
Why don't we just jump right into this dialogue.
我们不如直接进入这段对话吧。
Let's see what's going on and we'll be back in a bit.
看看发生了什么，我们一会儿回来。
It's almost midnight.
快到午夜了。
We're about to start a brand new year.
我们即将迎来一个全新的年份。
I know.
我知道。
It's exciting.
真令人兴奋。
A new year is always like a clean slate.
新的一年总是像一张白纸。
A fresh start to accomplish any dreams, objectives and goals.
一个全新的开始，去实现任何梦想、目标和计划。
Do you have a new year's resolution?
你有新年决心吗？
I was thinking about it but I'm never able to keep my new year's resolutions.
我考虑过，但我从来都坚持不了我的新年决心。
Last year for example I joined a gym and only went twice.
比如去年，我办了一张健身卡，只去了两次。
Yeah, I know what you mean.
是啊，我懂你的意思。
That's why this year I am keeping things more simple.
所以今年我打算简单点。
Maybe like getting together with friends I haven't seen in a long time or doing some
也许就是和很久没见的朋友聚聚，或者做一些
volunteering work.
志愿工作。
That seems reasonable.
听起来挺合理的。
We should get together and watch the ball drop in Times Square.
我们应该一起去看时代广场的落球仪式。
Sure, as long as you don't try to kiss me at midnight.
好啊，只要你别在午夜试图亲我就行。
Well, we can't break tradition.
嗯，我们不能打破传统。
It's bad luck.
那会带来坏运气。
All right.
好吧。
So we've prepared a couple of different words for you on language takeaway.
所以我们为语言要点环节准备了一些不同的词汇。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
The first word we have is actually a phrase.
我们第一个词其实是一个短语。
We have this phrase brand new.
我们有这个短语“brand new”。
Something is a brand new thing.
某样东西是全新的。
That's right.
没错。
We said that we are starting a brand new year.
我们说过我们正在开始一个全新的年份。
And that's just another way of saying completely new.
这只是“completely new”的另一种说法。
So I want a brand new bicycle.
所以“我想要一辆全新的自行车”。
It means I want a new bicycle from the store, not one from the garage.
意思是我想从商店买一辆新自行车，而不是车库里那辆。
That's right.
没错。
So it's something completely new, never been used.
所以它是全新的，从未使用过的。
So we're starting a brand new year and we're saying it's exciting because it's a great
所以我们正在开始一个全新的年份，我们说这很令人兴奋，因为这是一个很好的
opportunity like having a clean slate.
机会，就像拥有一张白纸一样。
So a clean slate.
所以是“a clean slate”。
Now this is an interesting phrase because you might not know what a slate is, but basically
现在这是一个有趣的短语，因为你可能不知道“slate”是什么，但基本上
it means that you start from the very beginning.
它意味着你从头开始。
So there's no history.
所以没有过去。
There's no nothing that you have to worry about.
没有任何你需要担心的事情。
You start completely new.
你完全重新开始。
That's a clean slate.
那就是“a clean slate”。
That's right.
没错。
So just imagine you're in class and you have the whiteboard or the chalkboard and you just
所以想象一下你在教室里，有一块白板或黑板，你只是
erase everything and then you start again.
擦掉所有东西，然后重新开始。
That's kind of what it means to have a clean slate, a new start.
这大概就是“a clean slate”的意思，一个新的开始。
Exactly.
完全正确。
And so we have a clean slate.
所以我们有了一张白纸。
We need to talk about what we will do with the clean slate.
我们需要谈谈我们会用这张白纸做什么。
And so one person asks the other, do you have any new year's resolutions?
然后一个人问另一个人，你有新年决心吗？
That's right.
没错。
So this is one of the most popular things during the new year's is people make a new
所以这是新年期间最流行的事情之一，人们会制定一个
year's resolution.
新年决心。
So a resolution is something that you have decided you will do.
所以“resolution”是你决定要做的事情。
I have many resolutions.
我有很多决心。
I will learn to play the piano this year.
我今年要学弹钢琴。
So in the new year, I will do this thing.
所以在新的一年里，我会做这件事。
That's right.
没错。
So it's really like a promise, something that you promise yourself that you will do in the
所以它就像一个承诺，你对自己承诺在新的一年里会做的事情。
new year.
So as you say, maybe start playing the piano.
就像你说的，也许开始弹钢琴。
That's right.
没错。
So we call that a resolution or if we want to be specific, we call it a new year's resolution.
所以我们称之为“resolution”，或者如果想具体点，我们叫它“new year's resolution”。
Now at the very end of the dialogue, we heard another phrase.
现在在对话的最后，我们听到了另一个短语。
This is quite strange.
这有点奇怪。
They want to kiss at midnight.
他们想在午夜接吻。
And the one person says, well, we can't break tradition.
然后一个人说，嗯，我们不能打破传统。
That's right.
没错。
To break a tradition or to break tradition.
“to break a tradition”或“to break tradition”。
That basically means to not do something that we usually do.
这基本上意味着不做我们通常做的事情。
All right.
好的。
So you can follow tradition.
所以你可以遵循传统。
That means that you do the same thing maybe every year.
这意味着你每年可能做同样的事情。
But if you break tradition, that means you don't do what you are expected to do.
但如果你打破传统，那就意味着你不做别人期望你做的事。
So remember that verb is to break, break tradition.
所以记住那个动词是“打破”，打破传统。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So let's review this vocab.
那么我们来复习一下这些词汇。
Let's listen to the dialogue again.
让我们再听一遍对话。
It's almost midnight.
快到午夜了。
We're about to start a brand new year.
我们即将迎来崭新的一年。
I know it's so exciting.
我知道这太令人兴奋了。
A new year is always like a clean slate, a fresh start to accomplish any dreams, objectives
新的一年总是像一张白纸，一个全新的开始，去实现任何梦想、目标
and goals.
和志向。
Do you have a new year's resolution?
你有新年决心吗？
I was thinking about it, but I'm never able to keep my new year's resolutions.
我考虑过，但我从来都坚持不了我的新年决心。
Last year, for example, I joined a gym and only went twice.
比如去年，我加入了一个健身房，只去了两次。
Yeah.
是啊。
I know what you mean.
我懂你的意思。
That's why this year I am keeping things more simple.
所以今年我打算把事情简单化。
Maybe like getting together with friends I haven't seen in a long time or doing some
比如和很久没见的朋友聚一聚，或者做一些
volunteering work.
志愿工作。
That seems reasonable.
听起来挺合理的。
We should get together and watch the ball drop in Times Square.
我们应该聚在一起，在时代广场看水晶球降落。
Sure.
当然。
As long as you don't try to kiss me at midnight.
只要你别在午夜试图亲我就行。
Well, we can't break tradition.
嗯，我们不能打破传统。
It's bad luck.
那会带来坏运气。
All right.
好的。
So let's take a look at those phrases now on Fluency Builder.
那么现在让我们看看“流利度构建器”里的那些短语。
So there's a phrase in here that I use all the time.
这里面有一个我经常用的短语。
We heard about this resolution to go to the gym more often.
我们听到了关于更常去健身房的决心。
And the person said, you know, I never really go to the gym.
那个人说，你知道，我其实从来不去健身房。
And the other said, you know, I know what you mean.
另一个人说，你知道，我懂你的意思。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
She says, yeah, I know what you mean.
她说，是啊，我懂你的意思。
And so basically we use this when you agree with the person, you understand what they
基本上，当你同意对方，理解他们
are saying.
在说什么时，我们就用这个。
Yeah.
是的。
It's almost like saying I had the same experience.
这几乎就像在说我有同样的经历。
So maybe I also belong to a gym and I never go to that gym just like you.
所以可能我也加入了健身房，和你一样从不去。
So it means I know what you mean.
所以它的意思是我懂你的意思。
I have the same problem.
我有同样的问题。
That's right.
没错。
So you can just agree with someone, completely agree with someone by saying, yeah, I know
所以你可以通过说“是啊，我懂你的意思”或“我懂你的意思”来同意某人，完全同意某人。
what you mean or I know what you mean.
我懂你的意思。
I know what you mean.
All right.
好的。
So, well, this year we want to keep things a little bit more simple.
那么，今年我们想把事情简单化。
And we said, well, maybe like getting together with friends I haven't seen in a long time.
我们说了，比如和很久没见的朋友聚一聚。
All right.
好的。
So let's think about this to get together with friends.
那么我们来想想“和朋友聚一聚”这个说法。
Lots of words there, but you can see friends, but to get together means to be social with,
里面有很多词，但你可以看到“朋友”，而“聚一聚”的意思是社交，
to hang out with, to do things together.
一起玩，一起做事。
But it's not very specific.
但它不是很具体。
It's a nice way to say just to be with your friends.
这是一个很好的说法，表示只是和朋友在一起。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe you are going with your friends out, maybe shopping, maybe to the movies.
所以也许你和朋友出去，可能去购物，可能去看电影。
So you say, yeah, I'm going to get together with my friends later on this afternoon.
所以你说，是啊，我今天下午晚些时候要和朋友们聚一聚。
All right.
好的。
So we can get together with friends as a resolution.
所以我们可以把和朋友聚一聚作为新年决心。
That's something we want to do in the near future.
这是我们在不久的将来想做的事。
But for now, we're going to get together and watch the ball drop in Times Square.
但现在，我们要聚在一起，在时代广场看水晶球降落。
That's the New Year's plan.
这就是新年计划。
That's right.
没错。
So it may seem strange.
所以这可能看起来有点奇怪。
It's not actually a phrasal verb or a colloquial phrase.
它实际上不是一个短语动词或口语短语。
There is actually a ball that goes down as the countdown begins to midnight.
实际上有一个水晶球会在午夜倒计时开始时下降。
And once it completely disappears, then you celebrate the New Year.
一旦它完全消失，你就庆祝新年。
So you actually see this big round ball coming down in Times Square.
所以你实际上会看到这个大圆球在时代广场降下来。
Yeah.
是的。
It's a way to count down to the New Year.
这是一种倒计时迎接新年的方式。
So people often say 10, 9, 8, 7 to the countdown and the ball will drop.
所以人们经常说10、9、8、7来倒计时，然后水晶球会降落。
And that means it's the New Year.
那就意味着新年到了。
So this is something that we refer to.
所以这是我们提到的东西。
It's something we talk about when we want to discuss the New Year.
当我们想讨论新年时，我们会谈到这个。
So we'll watch the ball drop together.
所以我们会一起看水晶球降落。
It's an event.
这是一个活动。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great stuff there.
那里有很多好东西。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue one last time.
我们为什么不最后听一遍对话呢。
It's almost midnight.
快到午夜了。
We're about to start a brand new year.
我们即将迎来崭新的一年。
I know.
我知道。
It's so exciting.
真让人兴奋。
A new year is always like a clean slate.
新的一年总是像一张白纸。
A fresh start to accomplish any dreams, objectives and goals.
一个全新的开始，去实现任何梦想、目标和计划。
Do you have a New Year's resolution?
你有新年决心吗？
I was thinking about it, but I'm never able to keep my New Year's resolutions.
我考虑过，但我从来都坚持不了新年决心。
Last year, for example, I joined a gym and only went twice.
比如去年，我办了健身卡，只去了两次。
Yeah, I know what you mean.
是啊，我懂你的意思。
That's why this year I am keeping things more simple.
所以今年我打算简单点。
Maybe like getting together with friends I haven't seen in a long time or doing some
比如和很久没见的朋友聚聚，或者做些
volunteering work.
志愿工作。
That seems reasonable.
听起来挺合理的。
We should get together and watch the ball drop in Times Square.
我们应该一起去看时代广场的落球仪式。
Sure.
好啊。
As long as you don't try to kiss me at midnight.
只要你别在午夜试图亲我就行。
Well, we can't break tradition.
嗯，我们不能打破传统。
It's bad luck.
那会带来坏运气。
All right.
好吧。
So talking about New Year's, everyone makes New Year's resolutions and people get together
说到新年，每个人都会立新年决心，大家聚在一起
to watch the ball drop in Times Square.
看时代广场的落球仪式。
Now this is more of an American thing.
这更像是美国人的习俗。
Have you ever experienced anything different for New Year's?
你经历过什么不同的新年庆祝方式吗？
Some other type of tradition?
其他类型的传统？
Because also here, they kiss at midnight.
因为在这里，午夜也会接吻。
That's right.
没错。
Well, that's a pretty standard American tradition.
嗯，那是个很标准的美国传统。
People will get together and they'll have the TV on.
人们会聚在一起，开着电视。
They'll have a party or they'll be with friends and they will maybe watch some fireworks or
他们会办派对，或者和朋友在一起，也许会看烟花，或者
watch the TV as the ball drops.
看电视上的落球仪式。
So I've done both.
所以两种方式我都试过。
I've gone out because sometimes you go outside, it's very cold, but you go to a bridge or
我出去过，因为有时候你到外面，天气很冷，但你会去桥边、
a park or somewhere public or the city government or the state will have some kind of special
公园或某个公共场所，或者市政府或州政府会举办一些特别的
fireworks display.
烟花表演。
So then everyone will watch the fireworks or watch a big TV screen.
然后大家会看烟花，或者看大屏幕电视。
And then when it's midnight, when it's the new year, then everyone will kiss.
等到午夜，新年到来时，大家就会接吻。
So everyone will kiss.
所以每个人都会接吻。
Maybe I mean, is it like just between couples or whoever's available, you kiss whoever's
我的意思是，这只是情侣之间，还是谁在场就亲谁？
there?
谁在场就亲谁？
Sometimes it's whoever is available.
有时候是谁在场就亲谁。
That's happened to me where you turn around and you say, oh, hi, I don't know you.
我就遇到过这种情况，你转过身说，哦，嗨，我不认识你。
So the tradition is you have to kiss someone at midnight.
所以传统是午夜必须亲一个人。
So this is for good luck.
这是为了好运。
Yes.
是的。
For good luck in the new year.
为了新年好运。
Yes.
是的。
So if you don't kiss someone, then you're kind of breaking the tradition.
所以如果你不亲别人，就有点打破传统了。
It's kind of sad.
有点可悲。
And it's unlucky.
而且不吉利。
An interesting way of celebrating New Year's, this is as we said, in the United States,
一种有趣的新年庆祝方式，就像我们说的，在美国，
watching the ball drop, kissing someone at midnight.
看落球仪式，午夜亲别人。
So we are really curious to know how you celebrate your New Year's in your country because maybe
所以我们很好奇，在你的国家你们怎么庆祝新年，因为也许
you have similar traditions or very different things.
你们有相似的传统，或者非常不同的习俗。
That's right.
没错。
And I know some places like Italy even have special foods you are supposed to eat to bring
我知道有些地方，比如意大利，甚至有特定的食物要吃，以带来
wealth and prosperity in the new year.
新年的财富和繁荣。
So let us know.
所以告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。
Happy New Year.
新年快乐。